The website has been successfully bifurcated

Day 00239: Sunday, 2015 November 01

I was supposed to help my mother in her classroom some more today, but she left me behind without saying a word. I don't know what her deal is this morning, but I guess I'll take this time to work on the upcoming website update.

I've finished updating the website's compile scripts, including the webpage template, the redirect page generator, and the weblog index page builder. I have also set up the index page that the website has been missing for so long. It's a basic English/Esperanto language-selection page with Esperanto greyed out for now, but at least it is better than the "this page has been moved to /en/" message that was there before. I've also updated every page that will remain at the //y.st. domain, of which there seem to be few of. Lastly, I updated the bulk of the pages, those that are being moved onion-side. I went through every one of these pages, including all 239 weblog entries.

After recoding the website, I worked on setting up the onion Web server on newdawn, my laptop. After a long debugging session, I finally got the server running. I still do not know why my old configuration does not seem to work, but I found hints as to what new configuration was needed by reading the new Apache configuration files. I am not sure if old configuration files honestly will not work or if I somehow messed up something that I failed to figure out. In any case, the website's new structure is now live. Having the server running on my laptop is inconvenient and I hope to acquire a dedicated machine to transfer the server to at some point. I might do some online shopping for one, but not before I manage to find a job.

The website seemed to mostly work after the first new compile, though there was one small bug at first. I'm surprised there were not more issues though. I did some tuning up of the CSS next. I've partially implemented some code to normalize the website's appearance across Web browsers, but it still needs some work. I will see what more I can do as time allows.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Backing up keys

Day 00240: Monday, 2015 November 02

*This part of today's weblog entry was withheld until Day 00244: Friday, 2015 November 06.*

I figured out what domain name I want to use for purposes that do not need to be fully disconnected from me, but that it needs to be known that they are not specifically my hosts. This would include an email server for delegating email addresses to people that ask me for them. (I don't know why people want an email address at my domain, but several people have asked for one.) This would also include subdomains granted to people who want them, should that desire arise. But most importantly, this would include works I start but would like to become collaborative. Collaborative works do not belong directly in Yst Domain, but I do not want to completely distance myself from them.

At first, I looked into getting //why.st., a pun on my main name. However, //why.st. has already been purchased. Unfortunately, the name is not in any real use, and is just being parked on an advertisement page. It is available for sale, but it costs $3500 USD, which is more than it would cost to get ahold of the more valuable //q.st. or //z.st., both of which are still available. I decided to see if I could fine a more obscure homonym. What I found quite surprised me. Both "wye" and "wy", seemingly the only English homonyms of "why", literally refer to the letter "y". They are the spelled out names of this letter. I had looked for the spelling of the English letters in the past but could not find them, concluding that there was no spelling of the letter names. Both //wy.st. and //wye.st. are available, with the former being substantially more expensive as the registry charges more for the initial registration of second-level labels consisting of less than three characters.

Looking into the Wikipidia article on the letter wye, I found its purpose in old English words such as "ye". It seems that old typefaces did not contain the letter thorn, which was still in use at the time, so wye was used instead. In old words such as "ye", the wye is pronounced like the modern tee aitch, not like the modern wye. so "ye" is pronounced as "the", the same as the modern word is pronounced today. Thorn would be another, and probably better, name for use as an entity that I am associated with, but is not truly or not fully me. It could be spelled as //thorn.st. or as //xn--vda.st.. Using the former, spelling of the domain becomes much more clear than that of //wye.st.. "Wye dot ess tee" sounds too much like my personal domain, //y.st., but "thorn dot ess tee" should let people know that the domain is //thorn.st. It is also further from my name even when the spelling is known, making it less about me.

I had planned on eventually setting up a website using the domain //notanumber.st., making the website about our need to escape being identified casually by numbers instead of names. I wanted to try to build on this enough to create a small, active community around it. However, I think I will instead try to build a community around the name Thorn, who will stand for three important virtues: freedom, such as the freedom to derive and modify, privacy, the need to not be under a microscope at all times, and individuality, such knowing that you are worth having a name and should never casually identify by number. I will try building software under the group name Thorn and see if anyone interested comes along to work with me.

I cannot post this part of today's weblog entry yet though. I'm not yet buying the domain and do not want it taken out from under me, at least not due to what I've posted here. Both to give myself time to think on the name and to align my payment due dates, I'll wait until March Seven to make the purchase.

I went into the big box store today to ask about their website's lack of job openings in our area despite the "help wanted" signs posted outside. As I had feared, instead of actually having any information on the issue, the customer service representative instructed me to use one of the computers in the back to apply. These computers ask you to either log in with current login credentials or create new login credentials. Not being at my own machine, I cannot use my encrypted password data base and paste the password. I decided to suck it up and try using a hand-typed password generated with KeePassDroid, but that only got me so far. The next step required that I answer no less than five "security" questions. Without my password database, answering those in a secure way was more than I was up for. I left without finishing the application.

I stopped in a restaurant on the way home that I had seen also had job openings available. Before I could ask about them, I saw the stack of papers on the counter, each with instructions for applying online. I took one and headed home. I will fill out the application online tomorrow probably.

Wowaname suggested to me that I removed my password from my account on Volatile, a new feature that she coded today or yesterday. Doing so requires having authentication via client certificate set up, which I have already done. However, this means that if I somehow lose my client certificate and not my KeePassX database, I'll have just locked myself out of my account. It is a more secure option though, so I copied my client certificate into my KeePassX database. If I ever lose that database, I'll lose more than just an IRC account, so it is safe to say that at that point, a lost IRC account will be the last of my worries. I have been trying to figure out how to back that database up somewhere that I can access without proving that I am me while not exposing it to a maraud of potential attackers. I haven't thought of any usable ideas yet, but I'll keep trying and keep the database backed up both to my mobile and my external hard drive.

While I was at it, I also copied my SSH keypair into the KeePassX database and moved my other TLS keypairs and onion keys into the database. I didn't move every last onion key I have into the database, but I moved all that were generated as permutations of //y.st. or //ystyst.mp.. Speaking of that, I found an onion permutation of //ystyst.mp. in my new onion keys directory. It must have been generated without my noticing one time that I ran the onion key generation script for a short while.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A flawed trust model

Day 00241: Tuesday, 2015 November 03

I tried setting up a hidden service on my mobile, but I could not figure out how to make it work. Orbot has an option to set up a hidden service. It says that it will automatically generate an onion address when doing so, after which, it will tell you what address it came up with. I figured that after it had set that up, I could find the file containing the onion key, then replace it with the onion key that my hidden service here uses. No dice. Orbot silently failed and did not generate an onion address. Next, I tried using the option that allows you to add configuration lines to the torrc file. Again, no dice. Like before, no error messages were output, but the HiddenServiceDir and HiddenServicePort lines seemed to have been ignored. I could not find any information on how to make it work on the Web, though wowaname said that it did not matter anyway; Orbot keeps the onion key in its monolithic Android application data file, so the key cannot be swapped out for the preferred one without special knowledge. I was hoping to be able to move the onion half of this website to my mobile so I wouldn't have to leave my laptop on at all times any more, but it looks like that is not going to work.

I have not finished reading all the email from my overly-full inbox, but I did finish cleaning it out. I've moved everything that still needs processing into a subdirectory so that I can actually see incoming mail. Most of the yet-to-be-processed mail is political. Everything else has been deleted, answered, and/or otherwise acted upon.

It seems that Marc With A C has released a new album, albeit a small one. Josh Woodward seems to have cleaned up his website quite a bit, too. His website looked professional on the outside before, but if you navigated around a bit, it seemed to have multiple layers. It felt as if a newer version of the website had been partially built on top of an older version of the website, which very well could have been the case. Now, however, the website seems uniform and consistent.

I found an issue with my bifurcated website setup. Due to the centralized security model used with TLS, the certificates used by the two websites are considered somehow less trustworthy than neglecting to use any encryption at all. You can usually tell your Web browser to bypass the flawed trust model on a per-website basis, but that doesn't fully solve the problem when using cross-site CSS like I am using to make the links to the onion half of the website visible when the page is viewed over Tor. The CSS file from the site you are viewing loads properly, but the CSS file from the other website is blocked unless both websites have been viewed separately and their certificates accepted by the viewer. On the clearnet website, this results in the links to the onion website remaining invisible even if the Web browser has been configured to use Tor. On the onion website, this results in the website being mostly unstyled. This could be fixed by paying exorbitant fees to a "certificate authority", but I refuse to do that as long as they continue to be expensive as they are. For a basic certificate with wildcard subdomain support, it would cost about $80 USD per year, and that would just be for the clearnet certificate. It's more difficult to get "certificate authorities" to issue certificates for onion domains, and from what I hear, they charge even higher rates to do so. Assuming Let's Encrypt will issue certificates for onion-based websites, they may be the solution, though right now, their services are still in a limited beta.

I've decided not to purchase any domains for the time being. I was going to wait until the renewal date of //y.st. in order to synchronize the renewal dates so that I would only have one renewal date to remember. However, I think it would be a better idea to just use my //ystyst.mp. domain for beginning my potentially-collaborative projects. It's a dumb domain for sure, but I'd rather not purchase another domain that I'm not even completely sure that I will get much use out of. The unfortunate side effect of this decision is that I'll have revealed the name of the group, Thorn, before making the domain purchase. The chance is slim, but someone may scoop up the domain I eventually plan to buy myself.

I've finally uploaded this website's code to NotABug.org. Due to the privacy issues that caused this website's bifurcation, I had to make the repository private. If not logged in, the repository's webpage even returns a 404 error. This means that while this repository functions as a backup copy in case I lose the website due to hard drive failure again, I can only retrieve the backup if I have not lost my KeePassX database. Keeping the KeePass database's local backup up to date is a lot easier than keeping the local backup of the website up to date though. The website is much larger, so I back it up to an external hard drive. Setting up the hard drive is inconvenient, so I don't do it every day. On the other hand, I usually back my KeePassX database up to my mobile every day that I've made a change to it, in addition to backing it up on the external hard drive when I back up the website and my personal files. For that reason, I usually have an up-to-date local backup of the KeePassX database but not an up-to-date backup of the website. A Git-based remote backup is easy to update daily though. I've also removed the outdated copy of the website from Github.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Reworking the website's compile script

Day 00242: Wednesday, 2015 November 04

Thanks to Git, I found that every time I sign a file, even if the file is identical to a file I have already signed, the signature is different. It seems that GnuPG is including information about the time the file was signed within the signature itself. Every time that I've needed to modify a page, I've passed an argument to my compile script that has erased the whole website and built it all from scratch again, generating new signature files. Additionally, certain index files relating to the weblog are regenerated every time, regardless of whether the the index is actually in need of updating or not. The signatures across almost my entire website therefor include the incorrect signing date. So now, on top of everything else I need to do, I need to figure out how to prevent the rebuilding of files that do not need rebuilding. I tried this before and got nowhere, but it seems I will need to try harder. I feel like this website is having to become ever-more complex. It's only supposed to be a simple website that acts as my home on the Web.

I've cobbled together a solution that might work, but I I will need to keep an eye on it over the next while. It involves compiling the entire website every time and only writing to disk as needed, as wowaname had tried to get me to do before. The main compile scripts now ignore the creation of signature files and the existence of current files, instead delegating this task to a new function specially designed for the job. The function checks to see if it has been handed a GnuPG handle, if the file already matches what is supposed to be written in it, if the signature file exists, and if the signature file is still valid. The lack of ability to delete the whole website has resulted in an inability to clear out deleted pages, so a hacky workaround has been put in place. Every time that one of the main compile scripts calls the new function, it also adds one or two keys to an array. One key represents the path of the file to be updated and the other represents the file's signature's path, if there is a signature. At the end of compilation, the script walks the directory tree and checks each non-directory file for an entry in the array. If the file is not present in the array, it is erased. I fear that this solution will not work long-term. The array will grow by at least two keys each day. The number of pages to process will grow by at least one each day. Recompiling everything and checking each file to see if we should keep it will take longer each day. What happens in several years when the website has grown into a monster?

Today I applied for work at that restaurant I visited two days ago. The job market sucks and I'm almost certain to end up in another stupid job, if I can find employment at all.

I found an issue with how I was trying to make links to the onion half of this website invisible. The CSS made the <a/> tag itself invisible, but I have a separator character between navigation links. As a result, if you looked before, you might have noticed two separator characters in a row. I've removed the check on the <a/> tags and have switched to using manually-designated <span/> tags. It is less automated, but it looks better when rendered. Making this change set off the rewriting of all the pages of course, causing the signatures to be recomputed once again. At least this time it was for an actual change to these documents though.

Having progressed as far as I'm really going to on this website for the time being, I decided to start work on some sort of Web software project. I need to get back into coding. However, I could not come up with any project that would actually do the world some good while also being at my skill level. So instead, I settled for returning to work on Minetyst. However, my thoughts on the project have greatly changed. Instead of keeping it hidden until it is usable, I've decided to upload the code as it is and just label it as incomplete. If other people have ideas and actually stumble upon the project, they are welcome to join me. I've also separated Minetyst from my name. It is now called Anarchy Game.

My mother just cannot wrap her head around the fact that my mobile doesn't do text messaging and that if she wants to reach me while I'm out, she'll have to use email. She just text messaged four different numbers trying to reach me. I have no clue who she messaged, but is sounds like nobody responded.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

sbuk7aqcxkoyipwv.onion.

Day 00243: Thursday, 2015 November 05

I thought about other options for naming the coding group that I want to get started. I five-character word ending in "st" would allow for a shortish domain using a domain hack with the //st. registry. However, the only still-available domains that fit the bill seem to be //foi.st. and //wre.st., neither of which I think are good options. I'll probably stick with "Thorn".

I have been trying to find the correct file to add setxkbmap -option lv3:lwin_switch,esperanto:qwerty to to make it run every time I log in, but did not figured it out until today. Looking through my old files from before the system reinstall, I found that last time, I had done it using the .xsession file. I cannot seem to find a file to add things to to modify the graphical session, but using the .xsession, I can replace the graphical session entirely. By adding startxfce4 to the end of the file, it becomes a minor tweak file instead of a completely-custom session.

I decided to try setting up TorChat today. I thought that there would be some sort of setup dialog and that TorChat leveraged your existing onion address, but that isn't the case. When starting Upon starting TorChat for the first time, it assigned me the address sbuk7aqcxkoyipwv.onion.. TorChat isn't just reached through the onion, it actively knows which onion address refers to it, so without any setup dialog, TorChat pretty much *must* set up its own onion address. TorChat's default scripts even seem to start what seems to be a second instance of Tor. To get TorChat running as I wanted, copied the line HiddenServicePort 11009 127.0.0.1:11009 from ~/.torchat/Tor/torrc.txt to /etc/tor/torrc, commented out every line in ~/.torchat/Tor/tor.sh, changed the own_hostname line in ~/.torchat/torchat.ini, and moved the ~/.torchat/Tor/hidden_service directory to another location where TorChat would not notice it. If TorChat sees ~/.torchat/Tor/hidden_service/hostname, it will change the own_hostname line in ~/.torchat/torchat.ini to match, undoing whatever customization you have made.

I am headed back to Springfield for the rest of the day. I may or may not write about what happened there tomorrow.

*UPDATE*: It seems that the plan has been changed and we are not headed to Springfield tonight. I still ended up away from home for a chunk of the day, and now that I am back, I have to get right to sleep as my mother and I are headed out very early. I had assumed that we would be back tonight because tomorrow is Friday and she has work, but it seems that she does not have work tomorrow after all. In fact, she has some appointments scheduled for tomorrow in Springfield. This means that the initial plan had been to stay there overnight, a plan that she had not communicated and that I had not prepared for. I need to start preparing for extended stays when we go to Springfield even when I have been led to believe that we are coming back within the day.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A day in Springfield

Day 00244: Friday, 2015 November 06

I had a strange dream last night. Specifically, I knew that I was asleep, but I was under the mistaken impression that I was aware of what was happening around me and even thought that I had a rather short conversation. Does this count as a lucid dream? I knew I was asleep, but I wouldn't say that I was fully lucid.

I've thought about domain purchases further, and I think that I will drop the name "Thorn" as a possibility for the group I want to start. Instead, I will attempt to generate several readable onion addresses and name the group after one of them. The clearnet domain I purchase will then match the onion address, making it easy to verify that the two domains are related.

My mother suggested that I discontinue the job search for a while and look into getting back into school. I am not sure how I am supposed to pay for school when I am unemployed and still paying off loans from last time, but I will probably humor her and look into it. She thinks that grant money will make it doable, but I doubt it. If she sees exactly how much it will cost compared to the small amount I can receive in grants.

My mother and I split up for a bit while she dealt with one of her appointments. I had not eaten in eight hours, so I let her know that I was leaving and went to grab food while I waited. She later tried to send me an email letting me know that she was done with the appointment so we could meet back up, but the message did not come through as it should have. I have push messaging set up on my mobile email client, which is supposed to cause new emails to come in as soon as the server receives them, but sometimes it does not work correctly. I did not receive any of her several messages until I had already met back up with her and had manually refreshed my inbox. I cannot risk her using this as yet another argument about SMS messages being better than email, so I have set my email client to not only attempt push email retrieval, but also refresh the inbox manually every minute. I fear that this will majorly detrimental to the device's battery life, but hopefully it will be worth it.

While we were in Springfield, we picked up the mail sent to our former address. A letter to me from First Tech Federal Credit Union said that they plan to send me a new debit card, just as Oregon Community Credit Union did. The strange thing though is that this letter was sent to my former address. As I verified once I got home, I have already updated my address on file with the credit union. It sounds like I will not be returning to Springfield for some time, so hopefully the card is sent to my current address and hopefully the card can be activated over the Web.

We stopped by Next Step Recycling to purchase a laptop for Cyrus, a desktop for myself, and a Wi-Fi card for my mother. It seems that Next Step Recycling does not usually carry Wi-Fi cards because as soon as they come in, they fly off the shelves. Being a recycling center, they cannot exactly order more. There did not seem to be any Linux laptops available and Cyrus doesn't use Windows. It would be pointless to purchase one of the Windows machines because we would be paying for a Windows license that we will not even be using. The only Linux desktop machines in the store were being used to demonstrate that the monitors for sale were functional, but I decided to ask about them just in case I could buy one. As expected, they were not for sale, but I did learn about a Linux laptop in the back that was for sale but hidden from customer view, so we now have a new laptop for Cyrus.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A day of distractions

Day 00245: Saturday, 2015 November 07

My plan for the day had been to sort onion addresses generated by eschalot, but I did not manage to accomplish that. The first part of my day was spent unloading boxes from the trip to Springfield as I thought it would, but then I ended up sorting food items such as canned and boxed goods. Before even finishing, I ended up going to my mother's school with her to help out in setting up her classroom, where I spent most of the day. We found that someone had come in and screwed her shelved to the wall without her permission and without alerting her to the fact beforehand. These are wooden shelves that she herself owns, not the school district, and they now have holes in them that she did not want. They also screwed right through he bulletin board fabric, putting a large hole in that as well.

While at the school, I decided to turn off the automatic checking of my email every minute because the battery drain is just too much. The automatic checking has dropped my battery life down to about eight hours causing the mobile's power level to drop almost to nothing as I sleep. While we are out and separated, it might be useful to have such a setting enabled, but for daily life, it is more of a problem than a boon. I also turned on the setting that allows Orbot to act as a non-exit relay node to give a bit back to the Tor network.

Once we left the school, we went to a Geocaching event. She had not told me what was happening there until we were on the premises. Otherwise, I would have been more reluctant to come; it was a film screening. Once the event started though, I learned more: these were films submitted to Groundspeak and we were to vote on which one was the best. My plan had been to quietly avoid casting a vote as I cannot in good conciseness vote on proprietary videos as they no doubt all would be. I kept my eye out for mentions of licenses in the credits though, and sure enough, one said that it had been released under CC BY 3.0, so I voted on that one. I was the only person to cast a vote in favor of this video, so it lost. After the event had ended, I asked to take a closer look at the credits as they had rolled by quickly and I wanted to verify the facts. I wanted to make sure I had the license and license version correct before writing about it. Much to my dismay though, I found that the license did not apply to the video submission as a whole. Rather, the video submitter had borrowed one of Kevin MacLeod's songs, and as such, had included his name, Web address, and license in the credits. It is awesome that Kevin releases his work under a free license, don't get me wrong, but it would have been nice if the entire video had been covered by a free license as well.

Upon returniing home, it was late and there was no time for sorting onions keys. I did perform a quick scan though and found that the key for //chattingwzknqyst.onion ("CHATTINGwzknqYST.onion") had been generated. If I were ever to use a separate onion address for TorChat, this would be a pretty good one to choose.

It sounds like I will be working in the classroom again tomorrow, so I do not anticipate getting anything productive done toward any of my own tasks for the time being.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Of onions and instant messaging

Day 00247: Monday, 2015 November 09

I finally backed up my GnuPG keys, both public and private. I think that all of my encryption keys of all types are backed up now.

I have added lines to the dictionary file that I use with eschalot to makes sure that any onion key that has three instances of the string "yst" in the first ten characters will be preserved. The chances of actually getting a match are slim, but it would be a shame to lose such a key just because I didn't include these strings in my dictionary file. I would love to be able to capture any key that has three instances of the string "yst" *anywhere* in the onion address, but I don't know a feasible way to do that while using word list mode. A hybrid option would be nice, something that checked each key against both the word list and a regular expression, preserving the key upon getting a match on either. I have tried converting the word list into a regular expression, which would do the job, but the regular expression output is too large for eschalot to handle. I tried cutting out words that I now know that eschalot would ignore anyway, but the regular expression is still too long to make use of.

I tried to set up XMPP service, but did not get too far. Hosted.IM offers gratis XMPP hosting at your own domain, but predictably asks users to set up SRV records. It actually checks to see that SRV records are in place too, so I cannot just use A records instead. The //st. registry does not offer SRV records, so I would need to seek DNS services elsewhere to use SRV records, but the only two places that I know of that do not cost also do not offer wildcard DNS records. I could seek a paid option, but my budget is limited. I also tried using CNAME records to point to corresponding records attached to a domain that Hosted.IM uses for people that do not have their own domain, but they use different servers for that domain, so the SRV record check fails. And of course, that assumes that the SRV record checker even understands and accepts CNAME records at all, something that I cannot check at the moment. I will probably write to the //st. registry later and see if they are willing to help. If they add SRV record support, it would potentially be very useful for other things in the future as well, and realistically, the worst they would do is either tell me "no" or avoid responding.

I have talked Vanessa and Cyrus into installing TorChat. I am in the process of generating a custom onion address for Vanessa so her chat handle will be more recognizable while Cyrus decides what kind of chat handle he wants to use.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

More bonus albums from Marc With A C

Day 00248: Tuesday, 2015 November 10

I finally reset my language learning account and started work on learning Esperanto again. I've stayed away from the lessons too long and I really should get back to making progress.

In addition to looking into collage grants, my mother has been pressuring me into trying harder to seek employment at the local big box store. Despite the bad reputation of the store and my insistence that they treat their employees poorly, she is convinced that it would be a pretty good place to work. To humor her, I tried something new to register an account online. The local jobs did not seem to be available online before, but once I have an account registered, I should be able to apply for the job in-store using their dedicated job application computers. Lately, it has seemed that all Tor exit nodes have been banned from the big box store's website, but I though there would be a strong chance that the job-seeking area would technically be on another website. This alternate website might not block Tor exit nodes. I used a proxy to reach the main website to retrieve the URI, and sure enough, it was a separate website that does not seem to mind Tor use. Much to my surprise, after having an account, the local job showed up on the website even though it is not visible when logged out. Also to my surprise, the telephone number field on the application was optional. I am still not feeling completely better today and I was only prepared to set a user name, password, and "security" questions/answers, so I only made it partway through the application. The website appears to save partially-submitted applications though, so I will work on the rest tomorrow.

Marc With A C has just announced that he is releasing Life's So Hard on vinyl. Like with the last vinyl album he released, if you act quickly enough, it comes with some bonus digital-only albums. These four albums are only available if you order by 2015-12-10. Like last time, I have no interest in the legacy vinyl itself, but I do not want to miss my chance to pick up the bonus albums. It seems that Bubblegum Romance also had a release involving some sort of bonus and I already missed that. So before I had a chance to forget, I placed my order for Life's So Hard today.

Speaking of music, Professor Shyguy announced an upcoming album a few days ago, I just had not had time to act on it, between life being busy and the huge number of emails I get daily. Fragmentation is currently available for preorder. I am not sure what advantages there might be to preordering the album, but I doubt there are any disadvantages (aside from the obvious inability to see what you are getting before you actually spend your money), so I tried to preorder the album. However, at this point, Bandcamp started trying to impose some sort of sales tax on me, no doubt because my Tor exit had switched and I was now sending my traffic from somewhere that has such a tax. I tried back later with the same result, so maybe I'll try back on another day.

Vanessa said that she was going to choose from the list of thirty-six potential TorChat handles that I have been having eschalot generate for her, but then she did not even look at them. Perhaps she will take a look tomorrow. In the mean time, I will leave eschalot running so she will have more choices when the time comes.

Speaking of tomorrow, it seems that school is out tomorrow, so we are headed out in the morning because Vanessa wanted to get a look at a somewhat-nearby beach at high tide a while back. I am not even sure if she remained interested for very long, as she seemed to become more reluctant over time, but our mother has insisted that she will make it happen and now has a day off to do so.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A new onion address format?

Day 00249: Wednesday, 2015 November 11

Marc With A C's bonus albums came by email late last night, but mainly, I have only listened to the introduction of one and a single song on another. One of these albums is a recording of a live show though, and his live shows always seem fun.

First Tech Federal Credit Union sent me an email this morning telling me once again that they will be sending me a replacement debit card in the mail. I hope they sent it to my current address and not my former address. Their first letter about the new debit card was sent via paper mail to my former address, despite my having updated my address in their records. The email continued that the card must be activated by telephone though. If the card comes to my current address, I will pester them about the issue right away online, explaining that I have no telephone to call from. If they send it to my former address, I will wait several months until the next time I am in Springfield, then pester them about it in person. Then I will pester them about the fact that they are still sending my mail to my former residence instead of my current one.

Vanessa, Cyrus, our mother, and I went to the coast as planned, but our mother seemed irritable all day. She kept picking stupid fights with us over petty things, then would act put off when we did not agree that she was right for having done so. On the way back home, we stopped at a discount store, and when the person running the till asked her to start putting the merchandise on the conveyor, it ticked her off. Just to be petty, she unloaded each can individually instead of leaving them in the boxes that hold a dozen cans each for the sole purpose of making the checker bag eaxh can, despite the fact that she knew leaving the cans in the box would make them easier to deal with both for the checker and for us when we got them home. And that is not to mention the fact that the extra bags were a waste of plastic.

Wowaname suggested that I might like the artist Tesslesstess. She is pretty good, too! I was going to buy some of her work later once I have found a job, but I accedentally purchased The pre-industrial town mill-wheels, thinking that I had Fragmentation in my cart, finally without sales tax. I must have put "The pre-industrial town mill-wheels" in my cart to see if that would have sales tax, as only Professor Shyguy's work seems to have this issue, at least both today and yesterday. I later also noticed that if I had ordered the physical casset copy of "The pre-industrial town mill-wheels", I would have gotten some bonus music on the take itself, which may or may not have been worth the while. I do not currently have the equipment to rip a cassette tape back into something digital, but I might in the future. I eventually did get Fragmentation preordered, but only as I was heading off to bed.

Wowaname sugested that I use <pre/> tags on my weblog index page and remove the <br/> tags, though i was reluctant to do that at first. Until now, I have been avoiding using that tag in most places because it seems like the easy way to do things, not the *right* way to do things. But the fact is, the <pre/> tag has semantic value. My ASCII calendars on that page do not function well in a variable-width font because they are meant to be displayed in a fixed-width font; this is exactly the type of data the <pre/> tag was meant to denote. On the other hand, I used that same tag on my usable ccTLDs page as a bandage so I would not have to figure out how to format the data until I had all the data I planned to put there, but before I had even completed the page, I had decided to replace it with a more detailed page displaying only information on the best of the best ccTLDs. I kept the old page, but because I had half-abandoned it, I never went back and fixed the problem even though I had finished the research and added all the relevant data to the page. I took this opportunity to clean up that page as well.

I am really liking the idea of the Ricochet instant messaging setup as a replacement for TorChat. The main advantage I see is that if you look at the Ricochet website, the example Ricochet address given is ricochet:rs7ce36jsj24ogfw. The colon makes it look like a linkable URI. If that truly is the case that Ricochet uses URIs with a URI scheme that can be set to open in the Ricochet application, the ease of reaching people that publish their chat handles properly should be easier. Instead of people having to copy and paste the second level of my onion domain into their chat clients, they can simply click a link that i have set up! However, there are issues. Like TorChat, Ricochet is built to use a portable copy of Tor instead of the system-wide installed copy of Tor. As two Tor instances cannot share an onion address, this means that you need a dedicated onion address for Ricochet and cannot have your Ricochet handle match your Web address. The Debian packaged version of TorChat uses the system-wide copy of Tor though, even if it does start a second instance of it. This is likely because when TorChat is installed globally, it does not make sense for it to use a dedicated copy of the Tor software. Messing with the TorChat scripts a bit, it is even possible to make TorChat depend on the main running instance of Tor and not start a new one. The way I see it, it is highly likely that the Debian packaged version of Ricochet has similar properties, but as Ricochet is fairly new software, it exists only in Debian Unstable.

I did not want to upgrade newdawn to the unstable version of the operating system without knowing for sure that doing so would help me make Ricochet do what I wanted it to, so I tried installing Debian Unstable in a hypervisor for testing. The instructions for installing Debian Unstable say to start by installing Debian Stable, then upgrade. The installation of Stable went fine, but when I changed the sources to point at the Unstable repositories and performed a dist-upgrade, the system ran into issues near the end. After all the software had been downloaded and a large chunk of it had been set up, the system suddenly decided that the file system was read-only. No more changes could be made. I tried shutting down the system, but the system locked up. After forcing the virtual machine to abort then restarting it, the system complained of file system damage and said that the file system needed to manually have fsck run on it. I do not need a system that is going to break before I can even get it set up!

I later realized that things might have gone differently, had I tried to do this on real hardware instead of in a hypervisor. I have to know for sure if this would go better, so tomorrow, I will swap the hard drive out, so I will not lose my current system, and install Debian to the new drive to try this again.

On #Volatile, devnull explained to me a bit how I2P's equivalent to IP addresses work. The main addresses are in base sixty-four, but a shorter hostname can be found by taking the SHA256 hash of the main address, encoding it in base thirty-two, and appending .b32.i2p. The I2P website compares these host names to Tor's onion addresses, but also links to a page on the Tor website explaining how onion addresses may become even more like I2P hostnames. The article is two years old, so I do not know if this plan is still in the works, but the idea was that Tor would begin using a full SHA256 hash, instead of the truncated SHA1 hash that it uses now. If this were to happen, I have no idea if current onion addresses would continue working. It is possible that the two onion address formats would work in tandem, with the format of the onion address being determined on the publishing side by the presence or lack of presence of some new variable and on the resolution side by the length of the domain's second-level label. However, it seems just as likely that the new onion address format would completely replace the old onion address format, either making old onion keys unusable or making them produce onion addresses in the new format. Either way, if old onion addresses no longer function, hyperlinks all across onion space would break. And what about TorChat and Ricochet? Would they function with longer onion addresses as they are, or would they need to be updated before they could accept chat handles based on the new onion addresses? Also, last time I checked, eschalot was unmaintained. How long would it be until a custom onion address generator was built that takes the new onion address format into account?

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

nfcbk2sgyblvdnq3.onion.

Day 00250: Thursday, 2015 November 12

I searched the case of my laptop to find the hard drive slot, but it seems that there is not one. Accessing the hard drive may be possible though the large panel on the bottom of the machine, but I do not have a scerwdrivers small enough to remove it at the moment. And if the hard drive is not one of the things directly under the panel, I might need to remove the whole bottom of the laptop anyway. For now, I have put aside my plan from yesterday to swap the hard drive out for testing Debian Unstable.

Previously, I tried using a standalone copy of Ricochet with the Internet connection disabled to prevent Ricochet from accessing the network and registering a new random onion address on my behalf. Once it start up, the theory was that it would generate the configuration files and scripts so I could rummage through them and figure out how to tweak them to use the main instance of Tor and main onion address. However, without an Internet connection, Ricochet had refused to start up. I decided to do some further experimentation with it today. First, I removed the file labeled tor, thinking that it was the copy of Tor that Ricochet would try to run. Then, I started Ricochet, half expecting it to fail and crash. However, it started successfully and somehow registered an onion address for use as an instant message handle: //nfcbk2sgyblvdnq3.onion.. The tor file does seem to be some sort of executable, but it is not needed. When run, it alone, it just complains about the port already being in use because the main instance of Tor is already using it. My guess is that Ricochet checks to see if Tor is already running, and if not, starts the standalone Tor executable that it comes with. The generated configuration files were of no help though. Ricochet's torrc file is blank and there are no executable scripts to be seen, leaving me without any clues as to how to jury rig Ricochet to use my main onion address. In fact, I cannot even figure out how Ricochet is adding an onion address to the network. The onion key file exists, but I cannot find any files that suggest that a new instance of Tor is being started or that any new instructions are being somehow injected into the main instance's configuration. I am not convinced that the Debian Unstable packaged version of the software would make things any easier.

I have found an option in my mail client that should allow me to sort and process mail faster. I might be able to keep up with email better from now on. It's not as good as what I was looking for, but it will do for now. Sylpheed has an advanced search option that allows searching by any of several criteria that the basic search option does not take into account, but the advanced search option does not allow one to select, read, delete, or do anything else with mail found using the advanced search option. It's pretty useless, actually. However, I just located an option that creates pseudo-directories that display only emails fitting your specified criteria. It is a bit of a mess, to be honest, and heavily reminds me of Windows' idiotic "libraries" feature, but it's better than having no way to sort by even basic criteria such as the "to" field on emails.

My mother is being moody again. She interrupted a conversation between Vanessa, Cyrus, and me, then got weird when we did not all drop our conversation and switch to her topic. Yet if she was in on the conversation and one of us had interrupted to try to change the topic, she would have gotten pissed off. She quite honestly cannot see that the two situations are the same thing. This makes me question her sanity. I also learned today that she does not understand that in most cases, she uses the word "literally" to mean "figuratively". As my brother often points out, the English language has become so broken that "figuratively" is a valid dictionary definition of the word "literally", but that is beside the point. When it was commented that she often uses the word "literally" to mean "figuratively", she honestly believed that she never did such. I am not even sure she understood what was going on once she was given an example sentence that she often uses in conversation and had it explained how the use of the phrase was not actually literal. This makes me question her intellect. I need to get my feet back on the ground. I need to find a job soon, before anything bad happens. I cannot be at the mercy of someone that has some wires loose without a backup plan. Tomorrow needs to be a day strictly of business, looking into job options and maybe looking into school. Nothing else.

I have been thinking a lot about onions today, seeing as I messed up and registered a third one. I think that I have been looking at them the wrong way. When I started out with them, I thought of them as novelty hostnames and did not take them seriously. Once I found out that Tor's use of the //onion. TLD had become technically legitimate by IANA standard, I started treating them the same as I treat any valid domain. It makes no sense to me to go out wildly registering as many domains as one can without purpose, onion domains have different properties than clearnet domains. A clearnet domain can be used to specify any host on the network. A clearnet domain's subdomains can be used to specify any other host on the network, whether these other hosts are related or not. However, an onion address instead refers to an onion router, a host that does not actually provide any service. Instead, the onion router accepts a connection and forwards it to a specified other host based on what port was accessed. (It is possible, and common, for the onion router to double as a service provider by redirecting traffic to the loopback IP address.) While different ports can be forwarded to different hosts, all subdomains always refer to the exact same onion router as the main onion domain. The subdomains are inseparable from the main domain and cannot be used for other hosts. Currently, my laptop is acting also as my server, so it makes sense to use the same onion address for both server activities, such as serving webpages, and client activities, such as instant messaging. However, this is not at all future-proof. It might be a better idea to single out services as much as possible by giving them each an onion address even if they exist on the same machine. That way, they can drift freely between physical machines as needed. Another possibility would be to give each machine a single onion address and have the URIs change as services drift. One more option would be to use a client onion address for services such as TorChat and a server onion address for services such as Apache. There are many possibilities, and I will need to put more thought into this.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Authored Nansyxlu

Day 00252: Saturday, 2015 November 14

Twitter keeps pestering me to get me to give them a telephone number, claiming that it is in case I lose my password. But if I lose my password, they have an *email* reset option. They do not need a telephone number for me to reset my password. I can only assume that Twitter wants a telephone number from me just to be nosy, but the joke is on them; I do not use telephone service.

I decided to split this website completely off of the main website; the two are no longer entangled. This one links back to the other for several reasons, but the other makes no mention of this one. There are no more hidden links that are only visible when Tor is in use and the Web browser is not being a pain. This website will from now on be standalone, but will continue to house my more personal side. This website has also been moved to a new onion address that better represents that split. The old onion address, quystystxtvdgyst.onion., was chosen at a time when I did not take onion addresses seriously and was chosen because it contains the name "Yst" three times. It is a ridiculous name though, completely unpronounceable. The new onion address, //authorednansyxlu.onion., is not only pronounceable, but is also not tied up in the identity of my main domain. It stands on its own merit. I suppose the use of wye as a vowel is a throwback to my main domain, but it is only slight. If the main domain were somehow lost, though I hope it never is, this domain would not lose its meaning the way that the old one would have.

While trying to figure out how to set up a wildcard certificate for the new domain, I found that wildcard certificates do not work the way that I thought that they did or the way that I think that they should. Specifically, as Wikipedia puts it, Only a single level of subdomain matching is supported.[5]. I do not even know why I try. With a wildcard certificate not actually being able to match the entire namespace of this domain and without any current intent to use the subdomains, I decided that setting up the wildcard certificate was not worth the hassle for the time being, as the only instructions I know of for setting up such a certificate ask that the user modify root-owned files. It's doable, and I have done it in the past, but I really hate modifying system files for tasks that really should be possible for non-administrative users. Putting a certificate in place and having the local Web server use it should require root privileges. Generating a certificate, however, should not.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

More job applications

Day 00253: Sunday, 2015 November 15

I filled out the job application for for a local discount store today, though it is one that has to be printed and handed in in person. I filled it all in before printing it to make sure that it was as neat as possible, then took it to my mother's computer because mine does not have a printer. Her machine seems to be acting up as usual though. This time, it was refusing to print images. As the PDF application did not have fillable blanks, I had converted it into an image and added text in the GIMP. From newdawn, I converted the application back into a PDF document, then brought it back down to her computer. Her computer was still not happy, and for a time, refused to speak with the printer. Once it finally decided that the printer was okay, it kept pausing during the print job. After speaking with my mother about this, it seems that her computer is being more cooperative for me than it is for her; for her, it will not even print at all. You have got yo love these highly-functional Windows machines, right?

Next, I finished filling out the application for the big box store that my mother really wanted me to apply for. I had something I wanted to say about the form, but I do not recall what it was. Oh, well.

My mother is one of those "normal" people that puts value in arbitrary calendar days and calls these days "holidays". In particular, she celebrates one of the religious winter holidays that tends to involve gift-giving. Today, she decided what she wants given to her, so it is my job to go into town to get it for her. I will pick it up tomorrow after handing in my job application, assuming the local store has it. If not, we may need to pick it up when we are in Springfield next.

Speaking of Springfield, it seems that we are going back this weekend after all, despite he having said that we will not return for quite a while. I should have known that it was too good to be true.

I tweaked my TorChat settings yesterday to use the new onion address so that I could discontinue use of the old one. I figured that I would update my siblings on this later, and did not do so right away. Today, however, Vanessa wrote to my new address asking if I was me! It seems that her client told her that my new chat handle had added her chat handle as a buddy, and because I am the only person she knows on TorChat, she rightly assumed that it was me. Cyrus has TorChat installed, but he keeps it turned off at all times, so no one can actually contact him. What is the point of that? I have also located a per-buddy option in TorChat that logs conversations to disk. It is nice to be able to go back and read past discussions, especially with the help of grep, but even better is that when this feature is turned on, you can see the recent conversation when re-opening a chat window to someone. This can give late responses some context so you know what is actually going on. I would recommend only turning this feature on if your hard drive is encrypted though.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Reconfiguring TorChat

Day 00254: Monday, 2015 November 16

I turned in the job application today, and found that the store I needed to reach for my mother's errand was in the vicinity, shortening the total distance I had to travel today. Her notes were a little unclear about one of the two items, but I picked them both up, then confirmed with her that I had purchased the right things.

We finally had time to set Vanessa up with a custom onion address for use with Torchat. While walking her through the setup, I found that she had greyed out options that were working on my end and vice versa. As it turns out, when I made modifications that prevented TorChat from starting a second instance of Tor, TorChat had detected it and made some adjustments of its own. My instance of TorChat had options concerting use of the main instance of Tor, such as selecting which onion address to use. Meanwhile, her instance instead had options concerning the "portable" Tor instance. (Her instance was not actually using a portable copy of Tor, but rather, a second instance of the global Tor executable was running.) Due to the auto-configuration that TorChat does with the portable instance, I thought that switching out her onion key and restarting TorChat would cause TorChat to reconfigure which onion address it identified as, but that did not happen for unknown reasons. One line in the TorChat configuration file had to be edited, but nothing difficult.

First Tech Credit Union did not get in touch with me today, despite having said that they would get back to me in one business day at the latest. I tried to check their website to see if the response had come in that way, but their website seems to be down tonight.

I started toying with a new project, some PHP-based Web forum software. I do not know yet if I plan to actually go very far with this, but I kind of want to. On one hand, it would be a nice learning experience, but on the other, I do not think that people will have much use for it. There are so many forum software options available that one more will not really make a difference.

I have uploaded the code for both my main website and this website, though I have kept this website's code private. If for some reason you need access to this website's code, get in touch with me.

My orange vinyl record shipped today! It should arrive in time to be useful as a prop for me near the end of the year. The shipping comfirmation email came with a tracking number, but the postal service's website seems to have banned Tor exit nodes.

I have just one quick reminder to everyone tonight: net neutrality still hangs in the balance. If you have time, write to your congressmen and let them know how important it is to you that net neutrality be saved. One of the government funding bills in play right now, if passed, would strip the FCC of the budget it needs to enforce net neutrality. Tell your congressmen to oppose that bill.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Roll Away the Stone

Day 00255: Tuesday, 2015 November 17

Josh Woodward just released a new piano tune caled Roll Away the Stone. The lyrics are a bit dark, but the melody has a beautiful, haunting quality to it.

Vanessa and I tried to head out to the store on foot, but our mother quickly stopped us, saying that she was headed that way anyway, saying that she was headed that way anyway and would drive us. She does not seem to understand that the walk is half of the purpose. First, we went to the grocery store, where we found canned vegetables on sale. The sign on them was incorect though, saying that the original price was $10 per can, with a sale price of $0.69 USD and a savings of $9.31 USD per can. It seems that one of the employees had made a hilarious mistake when inputing the non-sale price, and the sign template probably calculated the savings automatically. Next, we went to the local discount store, but Vanessa found a food item that had already been opened. I took the item up to the checker to show her that the item was unsellable, but she taped it closed and asked me to put it back in the freezer. Seriously? That can not have been legal. Not knowing what else to do about it, I put it back as instructed, but set it off to the side on the shelf so other customers might regard it a little more suspiciously.

I checked in with First Tech Federal Credit Union again, and their website is up today. I still have not received any email notification from them about the issue, but sure enough, I had a response in my on-site inbox. They had gotten back to me yesterday. The support representative said that she could activate the card on my behalf if I confirmed the last for digits of the card number. What I took from this is that they do not intend to make self-activation available for people without telephone service, but they are willing to work with us on an individual basis using a manual process.

I have begun the process of clearing out my political email backlog. I am working on signing all the petitions I have been asked to sign if I agree with them, sending any emails to political figures that I need to, and ignoring any any requests that I make telephone calls to anyone. As my backlog is several months deep, I imagine many of the emails have lost their relevance by now, so I have started with the newest emails and will work my way back. I will not post about most of these issues though, as they are probably old news for anyone that has had time to pay attention to politics lately and there are so many issues that I will need to address all at once.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I need to get out of here

Day 00257: Thursday, 2015 November 19

The //st. registry's DNS servers only allow the creation of A, CNAME, MX, and TXT records. Last night, I wrote to the //st. registry, asking if there were any plans to add support for other record types to their DNS services. After asking about other record types, I specifically mentioned my interest in AAAA and SRV records. I expected to be told that there were no plans for this. My real goal had been to express interest in the feature and get them thinking about it. Perhaps other people were expressing interest in other record types as well, so I would be one more voice. This morning, they got back to me. However, it seems that the //st. registry already has something in the works. Extended DNS management will be released soon with new nic.st website. However, the good news does not stop there. Because I asked about it, they have given me an account in their parking system, which in addition to the currently-supported record types at the main nic.st website, also supports AAAA, DNAME, NS, and SRV records. This is awesome! I have been curious about DNAME and NS records in the past, but with no valid reason for me to want them, I kept my mouth shut about them. The parking system also offers HTTP redirects and email forwarding, which may come in handy at a later time.

Why did the //st. registry give me this parking account though? Was it simply because I am a customer and asked about something that it could provide? Or was it because I paid a large sum for a short name, so now they gave me a little special treatment?

The new system comes with a tutorial, but it is written in Flash, so I cannot actually use it. It probably only covers basic things that can be found through exploring the system though, so I should be fine. The parking system had some of my records already configured to use the IP address 5.150.254.149. Trying to figure out what that address was, I entered it directly in the address bar. To my surprise, the parking page for the //m.st. domain loaded. I recognized this page as being the same parking page that several other single-character second-level domains under the //st. TLD use. Either the //st. registry has set these names aside, or the customers that use them already have accounts in the parking system.

I was going to set up XMPP service using hosted.IM's services, but their service did not seem to be able to correctly resolve my new SRV records. The records seemed to have properly propagated on my end, but not on theirs. I cannot help but wonder if the changing of DNS servers made it harder for the service to find the changed records. I will try again tomorrow. However, as SRV records allow the specification of a port in DNS records instead of in URIs, I am considering setting up my own XMPP service on my own server once I have a home server to work with.

Wowaname was working on a website redesign today, but was having troubles. I thought that I could help, but I did not get anywhere. The problem was that she was trying to vertically align text to the very center of the page, a particularly painful thing to do in CSS. I have only been able to accomplish this task once, and even then, I was only able to do it when the element to be centered was the only element within the <body/> tag. To be honest, I am not sure how wowaname accomplished this feat in her old design, let alone why it fell apart when the design was modified.

I started applying for work at one of the local grocery stores, but Cyrus and Vanessa wanted to me to go for a walk with them, so I put that aside for the time being. When we got back, I found that I could not log into my application account for unknown reasons. I also could not create a new account because my email address was already in use.

Next, I applied for work at a department store. The stupid application form demanded both a mobile telephone number *and* a home telephone number. I gave them my secret job-hunt-only land line number for both. It is bad enough that most employers expect you to be reachable by telephone, but requiring two telephone lines and/or a telephone line of a specific type is even more ridiculous. They also asked questions about whether family members fit into certain categories, and if you answered "unsure", they would ask who it was that fit into the category. If I am unsure of even *if* anyone fits the description, how can I know who they are? I ended up changing all my "unsure" answers to "no" just to get to the next part of the application form.

My mother is freaking out now. She says that she does not want anything to do with any of her children. I need to get out of this situation. I need to find a job so I can leave. This is not a healthy environment for any of us. She says that she will send the youngest two to live with their father and the child just younger than I is already in a stable situation on her own. I myself am in a very precarious situation though. I need to stabilize my life, and I need to do it as quickly as possible. Over the next while, I will probably fall mostly silent on my weblog. Most of what I am doing will probably be related to job hunting and looking for a place to live, so I might not have much to say.

I looked into the FAFSA as my mother suggested, but the deadlines are long past, and have been since before she made the suggestion.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Irrationality

Day 00258: Friday, 2015 November 20

My mother has gone off the deep end. She now claims that my veganism is a burden to her because I no longer eat with her. This is utter nonsense. Eating a separate meal does not produce any extra burden as I buy and prepare my own food. My former diet though, before I went vegan, was a huge burden to me though. My milk allergy made it impossible to be happy as milk caused me great depression. If she presses the issue, I might say that I would rather die than go back to the way I felt before. Until then, I will try not to eat in her presence in an attempt to lessen the impact of my separate diet. She also claims that my preference for free music is somehow burdensome to her. I quit playing my music around her already because she did not like it, and I do not complain about her music. I do not see any possible way that my taste in music could be a burden to her.

I have submitted my resume to a website that shows it to potential employers. I do not know how effective that this will be, but it seems like it is worth a shot.

The department store that I applied for work at yesterday wrote to me asking me to schedule an interview for on Monday. Unfortunately, this position is only seasonal, but I can continue my job search while working if I am hired.

I spent most of my time cleaning the house today in an effort to appease my mother. Seeing as I am eager to get a job and leave, it felt like a huge waste of time, but if it keeps her at least somewhat happy, it might buy me a little time while I continue my job hunt.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Leaving the laptop at home

Day 00260: Sunday, 2015 November 22

I headed out with my mother today to Springfield to work on cleaning up our former residence to prepare it for sale, as well as to bring more stuff back home. I decided that in the interest of avoiding conflict with her, I would take a risk and leave newdawn at home. She is still a bit moody, and the laptop might appear to be a planned distraction. If we do not come home tonight, I will have bigger problems than a late weblog entry though. As I have told her, I have an interview tomorrow.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

*Update*: We made it back to Coos Bay, and with quite a bit of time to spare. We were supposed to leave by seven, but my mother was not even awake when I wrote the original entry for today. When I made mention of my mothers continued sour mood, it was based on how her mood had not gotten any better since she freaked out as of last night. However, she actually seemed to be in a little better mood than usual, and in a lot better mood than she has been over the past few days. The complete shift in attitude like this is unnerving, but I should have suspected it. This is far from the first time this has happened. She seemed to be further off the deep end than usual though, and I honestly did not think that she would pull a reversal this time. I still need to get my life in order and get out though. The extreme mood flips are more than I can take.

I need to go in for my department store interview tomorrow. The position is only seasonal, but it is a job for now, which is better than no job, and does not require me to do something overly-objectionable. Also on the to do list if I remember and have time, I need to pick up stirring straws at the convenience store if they have them and I need to drop by the post office to pick up a change-of-address form.

Misted from #Volatile showed me a Web browser plugin that is supposed to allow the use of different proxies based on the domain name used in a given URI. However, this plugin does not seem to work. It will not allow me to add any rules or rule sets, and seems to block access to all non-onion domains. It recognizes onion addresses and sends them through Tor by default, but no other traffic gets through. I have been looking for this type of plugin though so I can reach I2P-based host names through I2P while reaching regular domains and IP addresses through Tor. I will continue to keep my eye out for such an application. I am interested in getting into I2P, but not at the cost of losing Tor. Tor&s onion addresses are officially part of the main addressing scheme, so getting cut off from them means being cut off not from an extension to the Internet, but being cut off from a section of the main Internet itself.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I am tired. Very tired.

Day 00261: Monday, 2015 November 23

After reaching the department store for my interview today, it took me a while to find the ofices that I was supposed to check in at. The instructions in the email were unclear, and in my opinion, incorrect. I walked around the store a couple times in search of them, and in the process, I found that I had chosen the correct outfit for the interview. My only particularly-nice shirt right now is black, so I wore it with black pants. Aside from one employee, every employee I saw was dressed entirely in black. I eventually asked an employee for directions to the offices; I still arrived at my job interview early, but the hiring manager was actually a bit late. From what the hiring manager said and from, it seems that this department store keeps in touch with employees by email, not by telephone, which is perfect for me. He said that he would get back to me within forty-eight hours, so the wait should not be too long. The hiring manager also said that if hired, I would get about eight to twelve hours. I assumed at the time that he meant per week, which seems way too low. However, once I left, it occurred to me that perhaps he meant that shifts would be eight to twelve hours long. If that is the case, it would be much more favorable. If hired, this seasonal job would last until January seventeen, at which point the hiring manager said that I might be considered for a more permanent position if I wanted it and worked hard enough.

After leaving the interview site, I headed to the post office for a change-of-address form. If Tor had not been banned from the post office websites, I would not need to be filling out physical paperwork to do this. Next, I asked for directions to the office of the Department of Motor Vehicles to pick up the paperwork needed to update my voter registration information, which again, would be unnecessary if the voter registration website had not banned Tor exit nodes. However, much to my surprise, North Bend does not have a DMV office, so I had to travel to the far side of Coos Bay to reach the DMV office of my own city. The problem with this is that to reach the far end of my city from my house, I have to first walk to the far side of North Bend, then turn and walk to the far end of Coos Bay. Because of a combination of the screwy road system and several small bodies of water that the roads do not cross, it is not a straight path and not a short journey. I made it to the office, but it took a lot more time than I would have liked.

I hurried home, fearing that I would not make it home before my mother. One of the things that she often gets weird about is my long errands. I really do not need to do anything that might set her off and flip her back into extreme anger mode. I considered skipping the trip to the convenience store, despite it being on the road home, just to save a few minutes. I decided against this plan though, and did drop by the convenience store to pick up some of the straws that my mother wants. Thankfully, she was quite late coming home as well, so I did make it home before her, though not by much.

The LED light bulb that I picked up at the discount store not too long ago is already acting up. Those things are supposed to last for decades! Cyrus thought that the thing had burned out, but I got it working for a short while. I kind of wonder if it was part of a bad batch, either malformed or damaged. The discount store does not usually carry such valuable merchandise, and now the thing does not even work correctly.

I located an Iceweasel/Firefox plugin that seems to offer a way to use a different proxy for domains using specific TLDs, but I also found an article claiming that the thing is proprietary. I looked into the plugin, and it is covered by the GNU GPLv2, so I made an inquiry to the author of the article. He said that he indeed knew about the free license, but that the company releasing it buried the license information in the frequently-asked questions page instead of making it obvious, as well as recommended that people use the proprietary version of the same plugin, instead of the free version. He also made mention of the somewhat-hidden license not being in compliance with the FSF's free software definition. I completely disagree with the FSF that this makes the software nonfree, if they even actually say that, but the author made a good point by bringing that up. Even though the software is free, do I really want to direct people to a company that is not promoting the fact that their software is free? I should either fork it of find a plugin offered by a company that is more transparent about the source code being available and reusable, preferably a company that does not make a proprietary version. And we all know that I have no intention of forking anything in the near future.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I did not get the job

Day 00262: Tuesday, 2015 November 24

Cyrus kept coughing on my after I got home yesterday, and now I seem to have his illness, right after I just recovered from my own.

Last night and today, wowaname and others have been helping me transition from HexChat to WeeChat. They are convinced that WeeChat is a superior client, and I think that they are trying to help me. WeeChat is very unusable in its default state though, and I do not recommend that to anyone, at least not yet. Once properly configured, it becomes pretty usable, but it is still a command-line-based application, which has disadvantages. While the mouse can be made usable, when made usable, it becomes impossible to select and copy text, so mouse mode needs to be toggled on and off. When selecting text to copy with mouse mode switched off, the command line does not take into account the presence of side-by-side sections, copying text from both. There does not seem to be a way to avoid this when copying multiple lines. There are advantages to WeeChat though. For one thing, there is no certificate leaking. In HexChat, if you do not set a global client certificate but you do set a client certificate to use with one particular network, that certificate will be sent for other networks that do not have a client certificate set. If I wanted that kind of behavior, I would have set that certificate as the global client certificate to begin with! Also, if a global client certificate is set in WeeChat, that can be overridden for individual networks, allowing one to use no certificate only for one network. I would have preferred that setup in HexChat, but there was no way to accomplish it. Finally, WeeChat allows the use of different proxies for different networks. HexChat only allows the setting of a global proxy that can be turned off for particular networks. In HexChat, I cannot connect to both Tor-based networks and to I2P-based networks. In WeeChat, I can.

Speaking of I2P, I now have that installed and running, though only for IRC use for now. Iceweasel, like HexChat, does not allow the setting of multiple proxies. I cannot get Volatile's short I2P address to resolve for unknown reasons, but the long base thirty-two address finally started working for me.

Marc With a C's album, Life's So Hard, came in the mail today. The post office had stamped the box with the text "MEDIA MAIL SUBJECT TO INSPECTION". What, did they open up the package to make sure it was the correct album, not a cover-up of the shipping of some illegal album? Is the postal service wasting taxpayer money fighting the copying of media? While I do not mind people seeing Marc's album, I find it ridiculous in general that we are paying to have the postal service open our mail and spy on us.

My mother has tasked Cyrus and me with the job of making a list of things we should have for the upcoming holiday that she celebrates, and she explicitly told me to include things that I can eat. After her recent outbursts, I think she deflated and might not be as on-edge as I have been fearing. I still plan to tread lightly, but perhaps she will be fine for the time being.

The department store that I interviewed with yesterday got back to me today, and is not interested in my application. I will need to continue my job search elsewhere.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Unreserved special-use domains

Day 00263: Wednesday, 2015 November 25

I stumbled upon a draft proposal that was to make several encryption-based TLDs official by setting them aside as special cases. This proposal, if accepted, would have set aside the //gnu., //zkey., //onion., //exit., //i2p., and //bit. TLDs. However, the draft was instead allowed to expire, leaving these TLDs unofficial and at risk for future clashes with the global name space, at least until a later draft set aside //onion. and only //onion.. It is still only a draft though as far as I can tell, so I do not know why the IANA has already set aside that TLD. If the draft expires before completion, it seems likely that IANA would need to de-reserve the domain, which having already been reserved, people were counting on being reserved.

Speaking of special-use domains, I did some further reading about the proper way to handle local IP address rDNS domains. I wondered why my system was not handling them properly. Instead of resolving them based on the local network's infrastructure, the domains were being said to not have records associated with them. As it turns out, this is the proper behavior. I thought that hosts on the network responded to these record requests in a manor similar to mDNS, except that the IP address of the machine was already known, so all you would have to do is ask it for its preferred host name, which would likely be its host name in the //local. name space. However, this is not the case at all. In fact, the proper action to take with these domains is to not treat them special in any way, and perform lookups as usual. They really do not seem like special cases at all, aside from the fact that a local name server is allowed to intercept them and resolve them according to a local database if desired. THis is no different from any other domain though.

Yesterday, I saw a post on the Floraverse website that mentioned the poster being sad about the removal of one of the then-official videos. Due to software issues, I thought that YouTube was blocking the use of Tor to view their hosted videos, so I used a third-party website that downloads videos from YouTube, then allows you to download the videos from their site. I later found the software issue on my end thanks to some help, but not before the video was taken down. Seeing as the video was under a free license and was no longer available from the source, I made sure to keep my copy. Though I fear it might not be as high-quality as the original, it was better than allowing the video to disappear completely. Seeing the post yesterday about someone being sad that the video was gone, I tried to contact them privately to give a copy to them, but the platform used for the discussion does not seem to offer that option. So I posted the video publicly. Glitchedpuppet, one of the main contributors to the official cannon and probably the owner of the website and domain, has already censored my post. He/she then politely requested that I not post the video around, stating that it had been removed in the first place for several reasons. I suppose the only decent course of action is to comply. Glitchedpuppet is working to create freely-licensed media, something that this world is sorely lacking, so it would be best if he/she did not feel like he/she needed to think twice before posting media in the future. I will hold onto my copy though, and now I think that I will probably download the full comic as it comes out in an effort to preserve anything that is later redacted (even though I will likely not be posting it publicly).

Marc With a C seems to follow his fans on Twitter, so he saw my post about the record he sent me being inspected. I had said that I thought that the postal service was trying to combat the shipping of illegal music, but he said that as best he can tell, that is not their goal. Rather, so-called "media mail" costs less to ship than packages of similar size. He says the postal service is likely checking to make sure that people do not send non-media as media mail, as the postal service makes less money if people do that. I suppose that is fine then. If you hire the postal service to deliver media, their job is to deliver media, not something else. At least the (probably) are not trying to censor media as I had thought that they were.

Devnull of #Volatile helped me get spell check working in WeeChat. Slowly, this client becomes more usable. I still find the awkwardness of following URIs to be a pain, but I might be able to get used to that.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I can get into Freenode!?

Day 00268: Monday, 2015 November 30

Today has been the first day that I have had most of the day to myself, so I took a break and did not get anything important done. I will probably get back on the job search tomorrow.

Due to WeeChat's being configured by default with Freenode's address and me setting WeeChat to connect to all known networks unless told to do otherwise with a specific network, WeeChat has been trying to connect to Freenode all day, despite their ban on Tor exit nodes. WeeChat actually managed to successfully connect to the Freenode network at least three times, though due to Freenode being unstable, the connection kept dropping. Whenever it dropped, it took several hours to reconnect, as it took time to cycle to a Tor exit node that Freenode had failed to ban. If Freenode had their onion addresses up and running, I would be able to create an account through one of these cracks in their anti-privacy ban wall, then connect via the onion addresses. I still would not be able to recommend that anyone use Freenode to host their channels, but at least I would be able to access the channels set up by communities that fail to see how awful Freenode is. Perhaps I will continue trying to connect and see if I can talk the administration into putting the onion addresses back up. After a few technical difficulties, I managed to register an account, so if I let it age before asking about Tor access, perhaps they will take me more seriously.

While on Freenode, I ended up invited by EllenAlien to a strange small IRC network that seems to be without a domain name. Upon arriving on-network, I was immediately questioned by the network owner, KindOne. KindOne seemed to be a bit defensive. I get the feeling that strangers are not welcome there, though once I told who invited me, I seemed to be free to stay.

Devnull of #Volatile showed me how to set WeeChat to actually show spelling suggestions, the other half of what a spelling checker should do. Devnull also told me about the /reload command, which allows you to reload the settings files after having manually edited them. Changing settings in-client is a pain, so this should save me a lot of time, especially when making larger changes.

I debated for a bit about whether or not to buy a new domain today, with today being the last day of the //st. registry's 70% off sale. I decided not to make a purchase for now though. I now know about this sale, which appears to be yearly, so that is enough for now. If I decide that I need another domain, I might wait until this time next year to get it on sale if the need for a domain is not urgent. I should not buy a domain now just because they are on sale, not even sure if I have a use for it or not; that is exactly what the registry wants me to do. I should use their manipulative tactic to my own advantage, no theirs. (Though I am calling the //st. registry manipulative in this case, they are still my favorite registry and I do not know what I would do without them. This sales tactic is perfectly legitimate, I just do not like how effective it almost was on me.)

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.